A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller vice presidential records, Susan Herter, Series 5 FA1211
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller vice presidential records, Susan Herter, Series 5
1975-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
United States. Office of the Vice President
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
Herter, Susan C.
FA1211
6.44 Cubic Feet 12 letter document boxes; 4 legal document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
The first portion of these files have art-related content, particularly those on the Vice President's tenure on the board of the Smithsonian Institution. Scheduling, transition office, and correspondence files follow. The remaining boxes cover a range of political topics and are arranged as received.
Scope and Contents
As a member of Vice President Nelson Rockefeller's administrative staff, Susan Cable Herter was responsible for managing the Vice President's office and overseeing his scheduling. These files reflect the range of topics that Ms. Herter administered: government office procedures; scheduling; art--particularly at the Smithsonian Institution, on whose board the Vice Presdient served ex officio; support of Native American tribes; redesign of the vice presidential seal and flag; and the U.S. bicentennial celebration.
During his tenure, Nelson and Happy Rockefeller oversaw renovation of the newly established Vice President's residence. Upon its completion, they hosted 9 receptions for members of Congress and the press to tour the residence on the U.S. Naval Observatory grounds. Ms. Herter maintained substantial files on these events, which are among the few records in this collection to reflect Happy Rockefeller's offical activities as Second Lady.
Lastly, as a top aide, Ms. Herter coordinated the extensive activities of the Vice President's transition office following the presidential election of November 1976. A portion of her papers were originally designated as Series 16: VP Transition Office Files. However, those records are integrated within the broader scope of this series documenting her service in the Ford-Rockefeller administration.
Vice-Presidents -- United States; Art; Presidents -- United States -- Transition periods; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1976
- Smithsonian Institution Board of Regents Files, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  Scope and Contents
  As U.S. Vice President, Nelson Rockefeller held an ex officio position on the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution. These files include board meeting materials and minutes.
- Smithsonian Institution Board of Regents Files, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10-20)
  As U.S. Vice President, Nelson Rockefeller held an ex officio position on the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution. These files include board meeting minutes, special project summaries, correspondence with the Secretary of the Smithsonian, and updates on specific museums. There is also a folder of correspondence on Vice President Rockefeller's push to add women to the board of regents.
- Smithsonian: Hirshhorn Museum, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Smithsonian: Museum of African Art, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- National Endowment for the Arts, Nancy Hanks, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Commission of the Fine Arts, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Baltimore Museum of Art, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Museum of Modern Art, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Art Planning Consultants, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Book: Art in the United States Capitol, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Guatemalan Textile Exhibit, Pan American Union, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Mexican Masks, Donald Cordry, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Italian Emergency Relief: Art Restoration, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Following an earthquake in northern Italy in May, the United States provided various forms of aid. Vice President Rockefeller oversaw the effort to provide aid to institutions with art collections damaged in the earthquake.
- Exhibition: North American Indian Art (London), 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 32-34)
- Art, General, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Support of Native American Tribes, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
- Sacred Circles Exhibit, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Texas Home Art Collection, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Materials relating to Nelson Rockefeller's art collection at his home in Texas.
- Scheduling Correspondence, A-J, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 40-50)
- Scheduling Correspondence, K-S, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 51-60)
- Scheduling Correspondence, T-Z, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 61-65)
- Meetings about Scheduling, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 66-69)
- Scheduling the Vice President, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 70)
- Transition: Administrative and Budget Matters, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 71)
- Transition: Authorized Liaison Officers, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 72)
- Vice President's Office Standard Operating Procedures, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 73)
- VP Staff Placement post-1977, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 74)
- White House Organization Chart, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 75)
- White House-related Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 76)
- Senate-related Correspondence, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 77)
- Vice President's Residence, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 78-79)
  Includes correspondence with Happy Rockefeler regarding the VP residence, which was also referred to as Admiral's House.
- Vice Presidential Seal, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  Nelson Rockefeller redesigned the Vice Presidential seal during his tenure.
- Nelson Rockefeller Biography file, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Nelson Rockefeller Medal of Freedom, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  President Gerald Ford adwarded the Medal of Freedom to VP Nelson Rockefeller near the end of their term.
- Correspondence Files, A to C, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 83-92)
- Correspondence Files, D to G, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 93-103)
- Correspondence Files, H to M, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 104-112)
- Correspondence Files, N to W, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 113-122)
- White House Fellows Program, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 123)
- Vice President's Incoming Memos, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 124)
- Presidential 1976 Campaign, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 125)
- Capitol Hill Club, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 126)
- Clippings and Remarks, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 127)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 128-130)
- Senator Henry (Scoop) Jackson, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 131)
- Sound and Light Project, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 132)
- Inaugural Medal, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 133-134)
- Wanda and Peter MacDonald, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 135)
- Unlabeled Correspondence, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 136)
- Vice Presidential Flag and Seal, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 137)
- Receptions at Vice President's Residence, 1975 September-October (Box 15, Folder 138-142)
  The Vice President and Second Lady hosted a series of 9 receptions at the newly renovated Vice President's residence (formerly Admiral's House).
- Carol Uht Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 143)
  Carol Uht was curator of Nelson Rockefeller's personal art collection.
- Irwin Gellman publication, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 144)
- Dinner for Galo Plaza, Organization of American States, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 145)
- Office of Science and Technology Policy, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 146)